( WHISTLING )
CHILD : ( MUFFLED ) Mum !
( CREAKING )
( GROANING )
CHILD : Mum !
( SCREECH OF METAL , GLASS SHATTERING )
Mummy !
Mum !
( CLEARER ) Mum !
I had the dream again .
( READS ) " And he climbed down that chimney ,
" straight into the huge black pot .
" And that was the end of the big , bad wolf . "
Did they really kill the wolf , Mum ?
I 'm sure they did .
I 'll kill the monster when it comes .
I 'll smash its head in .
It 's time to go to sleep now , sweetie .
It 's very late .
Can we read it again ?
" A long time ago ... just yesterday , in fact ...
" there were three little pigs and one nasty big wolf . "
( GRINDS TEETH , MURMURS )
( ALARM BEEPS )
( THUD )
- MOTHER : What have you done ? - It 's not broken . It just slipped .
I don 't want you firing things off in the house anymore .
Wait , wait , wait . Watch this . When the monster comes , I 'm gonna do this .
Please don 't !
BOY : Nothing in my hands .
- Nothing in my hands . - Stand still , please .
Look at me , Mum !
Come on , Samuel .
- Look at me . - Stand still , please .
Nothing in my hands . Nothing in my hands .
- I don 't want you making weapons anymore . - It doesn 't work if you don 't look at me .
This monster thing has got to stop , alright ?
Mmm .
Don 't do that !
Ready ?
Come on .
Quick . You 're late already .
( BAG RATTLES ) What have you got in there ?
See you later , alligator .
Here 's one for you , Norma . It 's got milk in it .
What ?
One with your milk in it .
I don 't want milk .
No worries . I 'll make you another one .
Ah , just where a woman should be . In the kitchen .
Hmm . Get to work , woman .
( LAUGHS )
Do you want a cuppa ?
Nah . I 'm heading for the dementia ward .
Aw . It 's a few years before you end up there , isn 't it ?
- ( LAUGHS ) - Right ?
Amelia ? Your son 's school is on the phone .
Oh , my God . Did he hurt anyone ?
A dart could have gone into a child 's eye or even worse .
I 'm going to have a serious talk with him .
Mrs Fanning , we 've had the talks .
We 've had the sessions with the counsellor .
We 're going to have to employ a monitor for him .
Monitor ?
He 'll be separated from the other children .
The monitor will supervise him one-on-one .
Samuel won 't cope with this .
He already feels so different .
I 'll have a talk with him . I 'll have a serious talk ...
Mrs Fanning ,
the boy has significant behavioural problems .
You know , Samuel doesn 't need a full-time monitor .
What he needs is some understanding .
I have 24 other first graders in that class .
Do you want me to put them all at risk because of your son ?
I think I 'll just find another school .
Mrs Fanning , you can 't just take the boy out of school .
You look after your business and I 'll go and find a school
that sees my son as a human being
and not just as another problem to be gotten rid of .
That is very unfair . We 're only trying to help the boy .
Please stop calling him ' the boy ' .
His name is Samuel .
We can see Ruby and Aunty Claire at the park today .
You can play on that swing you like for as long as you like , OK ?
Mrs Bruen hates me .
No , she doesn 't .
Just need a break , that 's all .
Don 't tell Aunty Claire what happened .
I 'll tell her later .
( BEEP BEEP )
- Mum , come and look at this ! - I can do it again .
Sam , don 't bother the lady .
No , no , no . That 's alright .
We have to go home and see Daddy , though , haven 't we ?
My dad 's in the cemetery .
Oh . That 's ...
He got killed driving Mum to the hospital to have me .
Samuel .
I 'm sorry . He just ...
No , that 's alright . I shouldn 't have ...
Well , your mum is very lucky to have you , then , isn 't she ?
We have to go .
- Say , " See you later , " Katie . - Bye .
WOMAN : The artist was so drunk , he vomited .
Right in front of his own installation .
Lost all these sales .
You 're not listening .
I am . I am .
So you lost all these sales and then what happened ?
Ruby ! Don 't play there . It 's wet .
Mum ! Mum !
I 'm gonna smash its head !
- Be careful . - Mum , Mum ! I 'm gonna smash it .
( SIGHS )
What would you like me to do for Wednesday ?
I can get their birthday cakes . That 's easy .
I was hoping Ruby would change her mind .
She doesn 't want a joint party with Sam this year .
- Oh . - Mum ! Mum !
She wants to have a princess party .
Mum ! Mum !
That 's OK .
We don 't have to come .
You can still come .
SAMUEL : Mum !
She just doesn 't want to share the day with Sam anymore .
- I understand . I understand . - Mum !
Mum , I can go really high ! Watch .
Maybe you want to celebrate his birthday properly this year , anyway .
- On the day . - Yeah , we 'll see .
( GROANS )
You know , Amelia , I just want you to be happy
and then this birthday thing rolls around
- and I end up feeling awful . - I don 't want you to feel awful , Claire .
We 'll be fine .
We 'll be absolutely fine .
Mum ! Look at me !
( CRIES )
Mama !
- Who do we have here ? - Hello , Mrs Roach .
You look tired , little one .
Have you been in the wars today ?
A few wars .
He 's had a big day , that 's all .
He 's just exhausted .
Poor little sweetheart .
Bugsy .
Come here , little girl . Hello .
You look tired too , love .
You OK ?
Nothing five years of sleep wouldn 't fix .
( LAUGHS )
I 'll put your rubbish out for you , Grace .
No , no , no . You 've just got in , pet .
I 'll do it now . Then it 's done .
( SCRATCHING )
You can choose one tonight .
Where did you get this ?
On the shelf .
( READS ) " If it 's in a word or it 's in a look ,
" you can 't get rid of the Babadook .
" If you 're a really clever one and you know what it is to see ,
" then you can make friends with a special one ...
" a friend of you and me . "
( LAUGHS )
" His name is Mister Babadook and this is his book .
" A rumbling sound , then three sharp knocks ...
" ba BA-ba Dook ! Dook ! Dook !
" That 's when you 'll know he 's around .
" You 'll see him if you look .
" Ba BA-ba Dook ! Dook ! Dook ! "
We might read another one tonight , hey ?
But you said I could choose .
" This is what he wears on top .
" He 's funny , don 't you think ?
" See him in your room at night ... "
Mum ? Does it hurt the boy ?
Mum ?
Does it live under the bed ? Mum ?
Mummy ?
( CRIES )
" How sweetly they sung , telling of the happiness and loveliness
" that lay at the bottom of the ocean
and entreating the sirens not to be afraid . "
( SAM GROANS )
( LOUNGE MUSIC PLAYS )
WOMAN : It 's that time of night again . Time ...
WOMAN : If that 's what the doctor ordered , I ...
Oh , yeah . Yeah . That 's what the doctor ordered .
( ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYS )
- MAN : Do you ... - ( SWITCHES OFF TV )
( BUZZING )
( BREATHES HEAVILY )
( MOANS )
Mum !
- It 's in my room ! - What is ?
- The Babadook ! - Oh , no .
No , no , no . This is not going to happen .
The closet doors were closed and now they 're wide open .
It 's just a book .
It can 't hurt you .
You 've had a big day .
You 're just exhausted .
I don 't want anything bad to happen to you , Mum .
Nothing bad 's going to happen , Sam .
I 'm gonna protect you .
( CLOCK TICKS )
( DISTANT THUMPING )
( FOOTSTEPS , CREAKING )
( TRAIN RATTLES ON TRACKS )
SAMUEL : Mum , it 's 9 : 00 .
He 's not running a fever anymore .
No , no , no . My sister 's gonna take him . Put it back !
Put it back or it goes in the bin .
( GROANS )
Sorry . What was that ?
Oh , no . I couldn 't get to the phone . He was vomiting .
Yeah , yeah , yeah . No worries . I 'll see you soon .
Samuel , no monster talk at Aunty Claire 's , OK ?
Samuel ... no Babadook . No nothing . Alright ?
( GENTLE MUSIC )
88 . Number 88 .
Two fat ladies .
Good , Elaine !
Another few days and someone could call out , " Bingo ! "
Number 11 .
Who has number 11 ?
Legs 11 .
Hey ? See what else we 've got .
5 billion .
Anyone got 5 billion ?
Beverley 's not very impressed with your bingo skills .
- Are you alright ? - Yeah , yeah .
No , I 'm fine . How are you ? How 's D wing ?
Fine . Yeah . Just a bunch of old people .
You don 't have to be fine , you know .
Just a bit stressed at the moment .
Why don 't you go home ?
Old cranky bitch ... she goes after lunch .
I can cover for you .
- You 'd do that ? - Yeah .
I 'll give you my pay .
Oh , no . Don 't be ridiculous .
You 've got a sick boy .
Life 's too short .
You 're so sweet , Robbie .
( SIGHS )
- You should go . - Yeah .
- Say hi to Sam for me . - I will .
( YELLS ) Where have you been ? You weren 't at work .
Rung you a million times .
What happened ?
Just scared the crap out of Ruby . That 's all .
He insisted on talking to this bloody Babadook thing all day .
Just talking to the air ... even freaked me out .
I 'm so sorry .
You need to get him to see someone , Amelia .
It 's not normal for a kid to carry on with this rubbish .
It 's not rubbish . It 's real !
Don 't you talk to your Aunty Claire like that .
Where did you get those firecrackers ?
You got them for me on the internet .
Well , that 's the end of the internet .
If the Babadook was real , we 'd see it right now , wouldn 't we ?
It wants to scare you first then you 'll see it .
Well , I 'm not scared .
You will be when it creeps into your room at night .
That 's enough .
You will be when it eats your insides .
I 've decided you 're not having your birthday with Ruby this week .
No cake , no games . That 's the end of it .
Samuel .
( TV PLAYS IN DISTANCE )
Ladies and gentlemen , Mum and Dad ,
life is not always as it seems .
It can be a wondrous thing .
But it can also be very treacherous .
( YELPS )
Don 't worry , Dad . I 'll save Mum .
I 'm gonna trap the Babadook like this .
And when it 's trapped , I 'm gonna kill it .
AMELIA : Samuel .
I was just putting something back .
- All your father 's things are down there . - He 's my father .
- You don 't own him ! - ( KNOCK AT DOOR )
Just thought I 'd see how you 're going .
Can I come in ?
Hey , matey . This is for you .
My mum always got me a model plane when I was sick . ( LAUGHS )
I 'm not sick .
Oh . I-I thought ...
No , he 's not , actually .
The truth is he 's so disobedient he can 't go to school anymore .
You said that 's not true .
How many 6-year-old boys do you know , Robbie ,
- who still believe in monsters ? - I hate you !
She won 't let me have a birthday party and she won 't let me have a dad !
( GASPS )
Ohh .
Don 't eat it .
The Babadook did it , Mum .
Go and watch a DVD and I 'll make something else .
- The Babadook did it ! - Just go and watch a DVD , Samuel .
MAN : ( ON TV ) Ladies and gentlemen , girls and boys ,
welcome to the great Martin 's DVD ' School of Magic ' .
Life is not always as it seems .
It can be a wondrous thing .
But it can also be very treacherous .
In this DVD ,
you will learn magic tricks to surprise , to delight
and perhaps even shock your family and friends .
Do you think this is funny ?
Oh , no . No . No !
- ( GRUNTS ) - Give it to me !
( SCREECHES )
Do you wanna die ?
( DRIPPING )
( PANTS )
( PANTS HEAVILY )
- ( THUMP ) - ( GASPS )
( SINISTER MUSIC )
( PANTS )
Don 't let it in ! Don 't let it in !
Don 't let it in ! Don 't let it in ! Don 't let it in !
Don 't let it in !
( FOOTSTEPS )
SAMUEL : Mum , do we have to go to Ruby 's party ?
I 've already got this doll , Mum .
Now she 's got a twin .
They can go shopping together .
- Off you go . - ( SAM GROANS )
He 's just really tired .
( CRIES OUT )
Go and play right now .
Claire tells me you 're a writer .
Oh , no , not really . Not anymore .
What kind of writing did you do ?
I wrote some articles for some magazines , did some kids ' stuff .
You just need to get back into it . That 's all .
It must be difficult .
I do volunteer work with some disadvantaged women
and a few of them have lost their husbands
and they find it very hard .
How 's Richard 's merger going ?
WOMAN : Oh , good . I mean , his workload 's just ballooned .
I 've got the kids 24 / 7 , it feels like .
CLAIRE : Tell me about it !
I don 't even have time to go to the gym anymore . It 's ridiculous !
That 's a real tragedy .
Not having time to go to the gym anymore . How do you cope ?
You must have so much to talk about
with those poor disadvantaged women .
( CHILDREN GIGGLE )
This is my tree house . You 're not allowed in here .
I 'm not hurting anybody .
Bye .
- Thanks . - Thanks .
How would your mum know if it 's real or not ?
She never comes to our house .
Mum told Dad she didn 't want to go to your house
'cause it 's too depressing .
The Babadook would eat your mum for breakfast .
- It 'd rip her arms off . - Shut up !
They feel sorry for me , Claire . There 's a big difference .
God , Amelia , as soon as anyone mentions Oskar , you can 't cope .
- That 's not true . - It 'll be seven years .
Isn 't it time you moved on ?
I have moved on .
I don 't mention him . I don 't talk about him .
What strain is that on you , Claire ?
RUBY : You 're not even good enough to have a dad .
Everyone else has one and you don 't .
I do have a dad !
I listen to your life day in , day out ,
and you never stop to ask me anything about mine .
I do ! I want to know how you are .
You don 't come round to our house anymore .
Because I can 't stand being around your son .
I can 't believe you just said that .
You can 't stand being around him yourself .
RUBY : Your dad died so he didn 't have to be with you .
- That 's not true ! - And your mum doesn 't want you .
- No-one wants you . - ( GRUNTS )
( THUD )
( CRIES )
What did you do ? !
She said I didn 't have a dad . She kept saying it .
Is she alright ?
Stay here and look after the children or do you want another one to get hurt ?
SAMUEL : ( SCREAMS ) Mummy ! She wouldn 't believe me !
Mummy ! Mummy !
( SHRIEKS ) Mummy !
- Mummy ! Mummy ! - Why can 't you just be normal ? !
( SCREAMS )
There is no Babadook !
Get out !
- Get out ! - Samuel ?
- Mummy ! - Stop this now !
Get out ! Get out ! Get out !
( SCREAMS )
Please help me !
There 's something wrong with my son .
I think it may have been a febrile convulsion .
That 's when the brain overheats .
- It always looks worse than it is . - I 've never seen anything like this .
We 'll have to wait until the tests come back .
All his other results are normal .
He 's obviously suffering a high level of anxiety .
Very committed to the monster theory .
That 's an understatement .
All children see monsters .
Not like this .
And it 's getting worse .
He 's becoming aggressive .
He could see a psychiatrist .
I can refer you .
Takes a few weeks to get in .
That 'd be great .
But can you just give me something for now ,
just to make him sleep ?
Um , just until ...
just until we get an appointment .
Please ?
I haven 't slept in weeks and neither has Samuel
and when we go home tonight , this whole nightmare will start up again
and I am really ...
I 'm really not coping .
I can give you a short course of sedatives .
Just until the tests come back .
Most mothers aren 't too keen on them unless it 's really bad .
It 's really bad .
These can make children feel foggy .
Perhaps some temporary nausea .
They 'll certainly help him sleep , though .
- That 's for one week . - Thank you .
SAMUEL : Why don 't people like me ?
AMELIA : Why do you say that ?
Ruby said people don 't like me ' cause I 'm weird .
Sometimes people say things that aren 't true .
You just need to take your medicine , have a big sleep and not worry .
I don 't want you to die .
I 'm not gonna die for a long time yet .
Did you think that about my dad before he died ?
Just take your pill so you can go to sleep .
I 've got the day off tomorrow .
Maybe we could do something , hmm ?
Will these make the Babadook go away ?
I think so but you have to promise me not to mention it again .
I promise to protect you if you promise to protect me .
Then I won 't mention it .
I promise to protect you .
Come on .
Can you stay here with me ?
Yes .
I love you , Mum .
Me too .
( EERIE MUSIC )
( DRIPPING )
( KNOCK AT DOOR )
( LOUD KNOCKING AT DOOR )
( TINKLING )
( SNAP )
( GASPS )
CLAIRE : ( ON PHONE ) Her nose is broken in two places .
- She may need surgery . - AMELIA : I 'll pay for everything .
CLAIRE : You can 't even pay your own bills .
Look , I really have to go .
AMELIA : Claire , I think someone is stalking me and Samuel .
CLAIRE : What ?
AMELIA : A book turned up at our place .
I threw it away but somebody glued it back together
and put it on our doorstep .
CLAIRE : Amelia , I just can 't help you right now .
I don 't expect you to help . I just wanted ...
CLAIRE : If you 're that worried , you should go to the police .
- I have to go . - ( HANGS UP )
( PHONE RINGS )
Claire !
Hello ?
( RASPY VOICE ) Mmm , Babadook ...
dook ... dook .
( DOOR CLOSES )
Hi .
I want to report someone stalking me and my child .
Can you tell us what happened ?
Somebody sent me a children 's book .
( LAUGHS )
And ?
And it contained violent and graphic images
of my child and me being murdered .
Can we have a look at the book , please ?
I burnt it .
You burnt it ?
Yes .
Well , unfortunately , there 's nothing we can do about it .
He 's been making phone calls to me as well .
What 's he been saying ?
Nothing , just making these ... noises .
How do you know it 's the same person ?
Because of what he wrote in the book .
The book you burnt ?
Yes .
( SINISTER MUSIC )
OK .
Don 't worry about it .
Did you get your things done ?
Mrs Roach has Parkinson 's .
That 's why she shakes like this .
Samuel , you don 't have to say everything that goes through your head .
Oh , it 's alright , love .
He wanted to know so we talked about it .
He sees things as they are , that one .
Oskar was the same .
He always spoke his mind .
Do you have to keep on bringing him up ?
( BARKS )
Hey , Bugsy .
- ( BUGSY GROWLS , BARKS ) - Hey .
- ( BUGSY CONTINUES BARKING ) - Hey !
( SIGHS )
Eugh ! ( GASPS )
Don 't come in here .
( KNOCK AT DOOR )
I don 't want to buy anything .
Are you Amelia Vanick ?
Yes .
I 'm Warren Newton and this is Prue Flannery
from the Department of Community Services .
My son 's only been away for two days .
He 's not actually registered at Babbage Bay anymore .
If I could just come in and meet Samuel
and get you to look at these papers , that 'd be great .
I 'm just in the middle of cleaning up the house at the moment .
I 'm sorry . There 's stuff everywhere .
Hello , Samuel .
I 'm Prue and this is Warren .
How are you ?
I 'm a bit tired from the drugs Mum gave me .
Not drugs . Tranquillisers ... from the doctor .
He had a fit yesterday .
I 'm really tired , actually .
PRUE : That 's no good .
May I have a glass of water , please ?
Yes . Of course . I 'll get you one .
It 's a real mess .
I just found this cockroach infestation .
I normally have the house sprayed .
I did actually already have it sprayed
but there 's this hole in the wall behind the fridge
and that 's why I ...
I didn 't mean a hole in the wall .
There was a hole in the wallpaper .
That 's where they were laying their eggs , I think .
WARREN : We 've caught you at a bad time .
I 'll leave you with this .
We 're required to come back in a week to talk through your options .
Here 's my card .
SAMUEL : Mum , I think I 'm gonna vomit .
( TV PLAYS IN DISTANCE )
WOMAN : ( ON TV ) What was that noise I heard ?
WOMAN 2 : ( ON TV ) I didn 't hear any noise .
WOMAN : Wind howling , doors slamming .
- I declare , I think this house is haunted . - ( GASPS )
Mum , I 'm gonna go to bed .
WOMAN 2 : Are you sick ?
WOMAN : Oh , no , Granny .
It 's only 6 : 00 .
Don 't you want to stay up with your mum for a while ?
No .
If you go to bed now , the pills won 't work properly .
You have to stay up for a while , sweetheart .
( SIGHS )
( TV PLAYS )
BOY : ( ON TV ) Where 's its mother , Skip ?
Koalas don 't leave their babies about .
Are you off now , Dad ?
MAN : ( ON TV ) Yep . Soon as I fuel up .
Tell Jerry I 'll keep in touch on the radio
and I 'll be back before breakfast the day after tomorrow .
AMELIA : ( READS ) " And the Prince and the Princess
" lived happily together in a beautiful palace
" for the rest of their days . "
( WIND HOWLS )
( CLATTERING )
( BUGSY BARKS )
( GASPS , SIGHS )
( CLATTERING )
( DOOR CREAKS )
( GASPS )
( CLATTERING )
( RASPY VOICE ) Babadook ...
dook ... dook .
( PANTS )
( CLICK )
( GROWLING , SQUEAKING )
( SCREAMING )
( GASPS )
SAMUEL : What are we doing ?
AMELIA : We 're going downstairs .
- Why ? - Because we are .
( GROWLING )
MAN : ( ON TV ) Iris , Iris , Iris .
WOMAN : ( ON TV ) No .
( MUSIC BOX TINKLES )
( MUSIC BOX WINDS DOWN )
( BUGSY BARKS )
WOMAN : ( ON TV ) Glass and mirror attachment .
Clean and polish shower doors or mirrors for a streak-free shine .
As part of your steaming special , we 'll even include the garment and upholst ...
Oh , I don 't want to give it to anyone at work .
( LAUGHS ) Alright . Give all my shifts away .
That 's just what I need .
I can 't help it if I 'm sick .
What do you expect me to do ?
You do that !
Mum , I took the pills but I feel sick again .
I need to eat something .
I couldn 't find any food in the fridge .
You said to have them with food .
I 'm really hungry , Mum .
Why do you have to keep talk , talk , talking ?
Don 't you ever stop ?
- I was just ... - I need to sleep !
I 'm sorry , Mummy . I was just really hungry .
If you 're that hungry , why don 't you go and eat shit ?
I 'm so sorry .
I don 't know why I said that . It was terrible .
I 've had absolutely no sleep .
I didn 't know what I was saying .
I 'll cook you something . Hey ?
What would you like ?
I 'm not hungry anymore .
We really need to get out of this house .
We 've been cooped up here too long . That 's the problem .
Do you want to go to Wally 's ?
You can have anything you want . Alright ?
Even ice-cream for breakfast if you like .
- ( ARGUING ) - Give it back !
- Stop it ! Sit down . Sit down . - No !
- Now ! - Give my drink back !
Sit down , please .
Where are we going ?
I just want to drive for a little while .
( GASPS )
- ( SCREECHING ) - Aarggh !
Mummy ! Mummy !
( BOTH SCREAM )
( RASPY VOICE ) Babadook .
( GROWLING , TYRES SQUEAL )
You ran straight into me !
I just bought this bloody car . What were you thinking ?
Oh , driving on the wrong side of the road with a kid in the back .
You could 've killed someone !
- ( REVS ENGINE ) - Hey !
Hey , what are you doing ? Hey ! Crazy bitch !
Hi , sweetheart .
Mum ?
I can call Aunty Claire .
I can call and she can come over .
Mum ?
Aunty Claire doesn 't want to talk to us anymore .
Mum . Mum , look at me .
It 's nice and warm in here .
I don 't want you to go away .
I 'm not going anywhere .
Mum ?
Mum , I don 't think we should stay here tonight .
I can call Mrs Roach .
I don 't want you to call anyone .
I just need to sleep .
- Mum ... - ( YELLS ) Leave it !
( WHISPERING )
VOICE : There 's something in the house .
( WHISPERING CONTINUES )
VOICE : ( YELLS ) There 's someone in the house !
( GASPS )
( WHISPERING CONTINUES )
( SILENCE )
( WHISPERING RESUMES )
( CREAKING )
SAMUEL : ( WHISPERS ) Mrs Roach can we come and stay the night ?
Gracie , I 'm so sorry .
GRACIE : ( ON PHONE ) Has someone broken into the house ?
- Sam said that ... - No , no , no . We 're fine .
Samuel 's just being very disobedient again .
GRACIE : Oh , I was so worried .
I told him not to call anyone .
GRACIE : He asked if you could stay the night .
No , no , no . We 're fine . I just have a headache . That 's all .
I really have to go , though , now , Gracie .
I 'm so sorry for troubling you .
GRACIE : Yes . Talk soon .
No worries . Talk soon .
I told you not to call anyone and you deliberately disobeyed me .
Do you want to frighten Mrs Roach ?
An old lady who can hardly walk ?
Do you want to make her sick ?
( YELLS ) Get that bloody thing off !
Is this the only way I can trust you not to embarrass me
in front of our neighbours ?
Is this what I have to do ?
I 'm sorry , Mummy .
It 's just that the Babadook made you crash the car and then ...
What 'd you say ?
I said the Babadook ...
The Babadook isn 't real , Samuel .
He 's just something you 've made up in your stupid little head .
I just didn 't want you to let it in !
I 'll make sure nothing gets in tonight .
Alright , Samuel ?
Nothing is coming in here tonight .
( SCREAMS ) Nothing !
SAMUEL : I feel sick .
If you don 't take the pill , you 'll feel worse .
Mum , I don 't think I need ...
I am the parent and you are the child so take the pill .
Good boy .
( MACABRE MUSIC PLAYS )
( GROWLS )
Ohh ! ( GASPS , PANTS )
( YELLS ) Mum !
( SCRATCHING )
Hey , Bugsy . Hey , sweetie .
Come here , sweetie . Hey ?
Hey .
Hey !
( BARKS , YELPS )
( GROWLS , BARKS )
( TV PLAYS )
Here we go .
There 's more where that came from .
Oh ! ( GASPS )
Aarggh !
- VOICEOVER : What 's the secret ? - ( MACABRE MUSIC PLAYS )
WOMAN : .. letter of Max 's , didn 't you ?
MAN : No , not for a minute .
WOMAN : Don 't lie . You called me a jezebel . Why ?
- MAN 2 : The north , east . - VOICEOVER : Natural corset .
WOMAN 2 : With fresh meat .
- WOMAN 3 : Only five ... - ( WHIRRING )
MAN 3 : You don 't wanna go in there all by yourself , do you ?
REPORTER : Police say the woman used a kitchen knife to stab her son .
His body was found in their basement .
The woman later attacked officers with a knife .
They drew their guns and shot her to death .
Little is known about the tragedy
but neighbours say the boy was celebrating his birthday today .
He had just turned seven .
( GLASS SHATTERS )
Samuel ?
Wake up , Mummy .
But you 're the one who 's asleep , sweetheart .
Don 't go down there .
It 's not safe .
Ohh ... I thought you were dead .
I thought you were dead .
We 're gonna be together .
You just need to bring me the boy .
You mean Samuel ?
( DEEP VOICE ) You can bring me the boy .
You can bring me the boy .
Stop calling him ' the boy ' .
I think it 's going to rain .
No .
( GASPS , PANTS )
( GASPS )
( WHIMPERS )
( SCREECHING )
( SCREAMS , CRIES )
( PANTS )
( GROANS )
( SCREECHING )
( SCREAMS , CRIES )
( GROWLING )
It isn 't real . It isn 't real . It isn 't real .
( ROARING )
( WOMAN ON TV SCREAMS )
Oh , no . ( WHIMPERS )
( BREATHES HEAVILY )
( PANTS )
No ! No !
- ( BARKS ) - Bugsy !
( BARKS )
( GROWLS , BARKS )
( BUGSY CONTINUES BARKING )
( BUGSY STOPS BARKING )
( TURNS TV OFF )
( BUGSY YELPS , SHRIEKS )
( BUGSY GROWLS , WHINES )
- ( AMELIA GRUNTS LOUDLY ) - ( BUGSY 'S NECK SNAPS )
( MOANS IN PAIN )
- ( SHOUTS ) - ( TOOTH COMES LOOSE )
( TOOTH CLATTERS ON FLOOR )
( BREATHES HEAVILY )
( GASPS )
Samuel !
( BANGS TWICE )
( SOFTLY ) Samuel .
Bugsy 's hurt and we need to get help .
You don 't want him to die , do you ?
Samuel .
Are you listening to me ?
Let me in , you little shit !
Let me in !
( VOICE DEEPENS ) Let me in !
Let me in ! ( GRUNTS )
( SHRIEKS )
You little pig !
Six years old and you 're still wetting yourself .
You don 't know how many times
I wished it was you , not him , that died .
I just want you to be happy .
( MOCKING ) " I just want you to be happy . "
Sometimes ...
I just wanna smash your head against a brick wall
until your fucking brains pop out .
You 're not my mother .
- What did you say ? - ( SHOUTS ) I said you 're not my mother !
I am your mother !
( LOUD BANG )
Run , run , run , as fast as you can !
( DOOR SLAMS )
Get away !
Didn 't I tell you not to play with weapons ?
( FIRES )
- Argh ! - Argh !
( DOOR SLAMS )
( FAINT KNOCKS AT DOOR )
I 'm sorry , love . I know it 's late .
I just wanted to make sure you were OK .
I 'm OK .
I know ... this time of year 's terribly hard for you .
And I know you don 't want me to go on about it , so I won 't .
But I just wanted you to know that I 'd do anything for you and Sam .
I love you both .
Samuel .
I 'm sorry .
I understand you 're scared .
I haven 't been good since your dad died .
I haven 't been good at all .
I 'm sick , Sam . I need help .
I just spoke with Mrs Roach .
We 're going to stay there tonight .
Do you want that ?
I want to make it up to you , Sam .
I want you to meet your dad .
It 's beautiful there .
You 'll be happy .
( SCREAMS )
Sorry , Mummy !
( RAPID BREATHING )
( GRUNTS )
- ( SHOUTS ) - Mum !
Mum !
I 'm not leaving you .
Mum ? Mum ?
( SCREAMS )
( LAUGHS )
You said we 'd protect each other .
I know you don 't love me .
The Babadook won 't let you .
But I love you , Mum .
And I always will .
( CRIES )
You let it in . You have to get it out !
I don 't want you to go away .
No ! No ! No !
Mummy !
Mummy ! Mummy !
( CRIES ) Mummy !
Mummy !
( DRAWS BREATH )
What is it ?
You can 't get rid of the Babadook .
( SAMUEL SCREAMS )
Ooh !
What do you want ?
No .
Keep breathing .
Put your seat back , sweetheart . 10 more minutes and we 're there .
No .
( HORN BLARES FAINTLY )
I think it 's gonna rain .
Stop !
( TYRES SCREECH )
( MOANS )
( LOW GROWL )
You are nothing .
( SNARLING , HISSING )
You 're nothing !
( HISSING )
This is my house !
( ROARING )
You are trespassing in my house !
( SCREECHING )
( GROWLING )
If you touch my son again I 'll fucking kill you !
( SCREECHING , ROARING )
( SAMUEL SCREAMS )
No !
( GROWLING FADES )
( LOW MOAN )
Mummy , don 't !
Don 't !
( MOANS )
( HIGH-PITCHED SCREAM )
( SCREAMING )
Watch out for your mum 's leg , little one .
He 's fine . I 've had the stitches out .
What time 's the party ?
Any time after three is fine .
I 'll see you in a few hours , then .
Bye .
Bye , Sam .
PRUE : That school 's a good choice .
AMELIA : I 've been doing a lot of reading about it so I think Sam will be happy there .
He 's been out of school over two weeks now . It 's time to get back .
We needed some time to sort a few things out .
Mmm .
Are you having a party ?
It 's Sam 's birthday today .
My first birthday I 've ever celebrated .
That 's not true .
Yes , it is . My first party on the day .
That 's unusual .
My husband died the day that Sam was born .
He got killed driving Mum to the hospital to have me .
Sam 's just like his dad was .
Always speaks his mind .
Well , parties are lots of fun , especially when they 're yours .
My cousin 's not coming because I broke her nose in two places .
( TEACUP RATTLES GENTLY )
I 'll take that for you .
Good shot .
Look , there 's another one !
Where 's your bowl ?
Wow . You 've got a lot today .
Am I ever gonna see it ?
One day , when you 're bigger .
You go outside , and you don 't come in until I tell you .
( GROWLING )
Argh !
It 's alright . ( GASPS ) It 's alright .
It 's alright .
Shhh ...
How was it ?
It was pretty quiet today .
Come here .
It 's getting much better , Mum .
Wait !
I have a new trick .
Life is not always as it seems .
Nothing in my hands . Nothing in my hands .
- That 's great ! - I haven 't finished .
Abracadabra !
How did you do that ?
( LAUGHS )
Come here , you . Come here .
Happy birthday , sweetheart .